本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：feilixiaozi CS漫画家小明 潇湘月影 香茗小焙 Reginamoon 真月镜威
翻译：王大可 杳杳 杨一勾 某羽 小饭 鱼小姐 木浅薰
时间轴：姜姜  倩倩  spohy     校对：油炸电风扇   潇湘月影
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第四集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你没经过我的允许就接了这个案子
You took this case without running it by me.
-杰西卡  -够了  撤销
- Jessica-- - That's enough. Dump it.
否则我去撤销
Or I will.
你觉得这案子能赢吗
You think this case is a winner?
能赢
I do.
那你觉得我们一起做如何
Then what do you say we do it together?
我怕你们最终会憎恨对方
I'm afraid you're gonna end up hating each other.
如果我足够幸运的话将会因为很多事情和他争斗
If I'm lucky, I'm gonna fight with him about a lot of things.
所以为什么不以一次站在同一边的斗争作为开始呢
Why not start with a fight where we're both on the same side?
这是哈维最近三个案子的收益表
This is harvey's last three income statements,
我发现它们被放在复印机里
and I found them sitting in the copy machine.
是你主动为我工作的
You came to work for me.
你做决定的时候知道我是什么样的人
You knew who I was when you did,
你该作出决定了
so now it's time for you to decide.
你到底要不要站在我这边
Are you with me or not?
因为你总说  "人一旦选择了立场
You always said, once you pick a side,
就要忠于他的立场
if you're not loyal to that side,
不然他算什么人呢"
then who the hell are you?
那你在选择一个会做出这种事的人之前
You should've thought of that before you picked someone
就该好好想想
who would do something like this in the first place.
你再跟杰克・索罗夫一伙儿
You ever take sides with Jack Soloff against me again,
我会灭了你
I will bury you.
你看起来很开心啊
Well, you look happy.
是贝琪刚告诉苏西她确实很喜欢你吗
Becky just tell Susie she like-likes you?
其实是凯尔顿保险刚告诉罗伯特・赞恩
Eh, more like Kelton insurance just told Robert Zane
他们确实很害怕我们
they're scared-scared of us.
你们收到和解报价了
You got a settlement offer?
就像他说的那样
Just like he said we would.
不得不表扬他一下  他把他们耍得很漂亮
I got to hand it to him, he played them perfectly.
是吗
Did he now?
什么
What?
没事
Nothing.
听着  我收回关于贝琪的话
Look, I take it back about Becky.
这里唯一春心萌动的人是你
The only one with a crush around here is you.
看来有些人担心罗伯特・赞恩
Sounds like someone's worried that Robert Zane
也许会比他强
might be better than him.
想得美  泰格  但魔术师什么时候怕过伯德
Nice try, Tiger, but did Magic ever worry about Bird?
首先  是的  他怕过
First of all, yes, he did.
其次  你有没有意识到
Second of all, you realize
在这个比喻里你才是白人
you're the white guy in this scenario, right?
我知道在任何比喻里我都是比较厉害的那个
I know I'm the bigger badass in every scenario.
好吧厉害先生  你是谁  魔术师还是伯德
Okay, Mr. Badass, which one are you, Magic or Bird?
我觉得我们都很清楚我是
I think we both know I'm...
乔丹
Jordan.
不如你去找你的男友罗伯特・赞恩吧
Hey, why don't you go meet your boyfriend Robert Zane?
我好像落了东西在保安那里
I think I just left something at security.
看看现在是谁喜欢某人了
Oh. Look who like-likes someone now.
女士  上次我放了
Ma'am, the last time I let someone up
没有预约的人上去
that he wasn't expecting,
他威胁要把我处决
he threatened to have me executed.
我知道他肯定是那样说的  但我跟你说
I'm sure he did, but I'm telling you that--
格蕾琴肯定是忘了打电话下来了  卡尔
That Gretchen obviously forgot to phone down, Carl,
因为我们约了就这个时间开会
because we have a meeting scheduled for right now.
但她刚才不是这么...
That isn't what she just--
卡尔
Carl.
和你开会  真的吗
A meeting with you. Really?
我敢向你保证我比
I promise I'm much better-looking
你要见的那个人帅
than whoever you were supposed to meet.
你说的太对了
You have no idea how right you are.
但我看你好像正要出去
But I could have sworn you were just on your way out.
没关系的
Oh, that's not a problem.
市长可以等
The mayor can wait.
但我觉得州长不一定可以
But I'm not sure the Governor can.
你是在跟我比名头吗
Are you trying to out-name-drop me?
如果是的话  我觉得我刚赢了
If I were, I think I just did.
但我告诉你个小秘密
But I'll let you in on a little secret.
我一点都不在乎名头
I don't really care about names that much.
如果你不在意名头
Well, if you don't care about names,
那我们就跳过自我介绍阶段
why don't we skip the introductions
直接吃早餐吧
and just get down to breakfast?
如果我已经吃过了呢
What if I already had breakfast?
我是说明早  在我的厨房
I'm talking about tomorrow morning, in my kitchen.
或者你的  我是说  你看起来有个好住处
Or yours, I mean, you look like you have a nice place.
虽然很有诱惑力  但下次吧
As tempting as that is, maybe another time.
祝你开会顺利
Good luck in your meeting.
我最喜欢的讨人厌律师最近好吗
So how's my favorite pain-in-the-ass lawyer?
我以为路易是你最喜欢的讨人厌律师
I thought Louis was your favorite pain-in-the-ass lawyer.
没错  但我做这个
He is, but Louis isn't responsible
可不是为了路易
for me getting to work on this.
你在给我们的案子干粗活儿
You're doing the grunt work on our case?
我托了关系揽下这活儿  觉得这可以
I pulled some strings, thought it might give us
让我们有机会一起工作
a chance to work together.
你知道我已经订婚了  是吧
You know I'm engaged, right?
是的  迈克  这是我的计划
Yes, Mike, that's my plan,
把你从我老板女儿的身边偷走
to steal you from my boss's daughter.
事实如此  木已成舟
It's a thing. It's been done.
我不是来偷走你的心的
Well, I didn't come here to steal you.
我是来感谢你的
I came here to thank you.
为什么
For what?
拜托  迈克
Come on, Mike.
我被解雇了  而两天后
I get fired, and two days later,
瑞秋的父亲给我提供了职位
I get an offer from Rachel's father?
不论你是怎么做到的  我都欠你一个人情
Whatever you did, I owe you one.
事实上  你欠瑞秋的人情
Actually, you owe Rachel one.
不是吧
No shit.
就是
Shit.
该死
shiiit.
顺便说  你进错会议室了
By the way, you're in the wrong conference room.
好吧  埃斯特  你来这干什么
Okay, Esther, what are you doing here?
怎么  一个女人  不能在路过时
What, a woman can't stop by
顺便来看看她爱的哥哥吗
to see her brother, who she loves?
拜托  你太清楚了  我们之间没爱
Please, you know damn well we don't love each other.
这么说的话  我要请律师
In that case, I need a lawyer.
你  要律师干嘛
You? For what?
你卖的松饼让人感染沙门氏菌了吗
Did you give someone salmonella with your stupid muffins?
我要离婚
I'm getting a divorce.
好吧
Well, good.
我第一次见他就觉得他是个累赘
I knew that guy was dead weight the second I met him.
我知道  你在婚礼致辞的时候就这么说的
I know, I think that was your speech at our wedding.
你的同情很感人
And your sympathy is touching,
但我不是跑来证明你有多正确的
but I didn't come here to vindicate you.
我知道
No, I know you didn't.
你是来让我
You came to get me
帮你干掉杰弗里的  我会的
to slaughter Jeffrey for you, and I will.
等我收拾完  他想拉屎都没有夜壶用
When I'm done with him, he won't have a pot to shit in.
夜壶是用来尿的
It's "Piss in".
路易  我不想让你干掉杰弗里
And, Louis, I don't want you to slaughter Jeffrey.
为什么
Why the hell not?
因为我想让哈维・斯佩克特来做
Because I want Harvey Specter to.
再说一遍
Come again?
你说过  他是城里最好的律师
You said he was the best attorney in the city.
不  埃斯特  我说的是他是我最好的朋友
No, Esther, I told you he was my best friend.
十年级的时候
Which is exactly what you said
你也是这么说杰里米・翰舍的
about Jeremy Henschell in tenth grade,
而这句话真正的意思是
which really meant
你远远地崇拜着他
you worshipped him from afar,
写的日记都是关于他的
you wrote in your diary about him,
而且你俩都没一起玩过
and you never actually hung out.
你发誓说没过看我的日记
Okay, you swore you never read my diary.
你也发誓说没偷窥我和杰里米
And you swore you didn't spy on me and Jeremy.
拜托  就那么一次
Oh, please, that was one time.
我是要去拿杯牛奶
I was on my way to get a glass of milk.
而且你可能不知道
And for your information,
从那以后  我一直乳糖过敏
I've been lactose intolerant ever since.
路易  是你帮我找哈维
Louis, are you gonna get me Harvey,
还是我自己去找
or do I have to get him myself?
哈维现在不接新客户
Harvey is not taking on any new clients right now,
而且未来几年都不在城里
and he's out of town for the next few years.
路易  我知道你什么意思
Louis, I know what you're doing.
你以为我找哈维
You think I want Harvey
是因为我觉得你不够好
because I don't think you're good enough.
你错了
You're wrong.
我知道你有多出色
I know how good you are.
但这是我的私事
But this is personal for me,
那就意味着  那也是你的私事
which means it will be personal for you,
我不能让你参与
and I can't have that.
所以拜托  帮我去找哈维好吗
So please, will you get me Harvey?
我帮你找哈维
I'll make it happen.
谢谢  路易
Thank you, Louis.
刚才那是埃斯特
That was Esther?
对  我知道你要说什么
Yes, I know what you're gonna say--
我们是一个模子刻出来的
we look exactly alike.
我没想说...
That actually wasn't...
我知道  我要是带上假发就是那样
I get it--it's like looking at me in a wig.
我已经听过上千遍了
I've heard it a thousand times.
对  你们相像得不可思议
Yeah, the resemblance is uncanny.
怎么了
What?
我只是好奇你干嘛不赶快起身去找哈维
I'm just wondering why you're not getting up to go ask Harvey.
因为我不打算去找他帮忙
Because I'm not gonna ask him.
我打算省点时间直接告诉她哈维拒绝了
I'm gonna save some time and tell her he said no.
-路易...  -唐娜
- Louis-- - Donna,
我们都清楚哈维超级生我的气
we all know that Harvey's furious at me.
他没可能会答应帮忙的
There's no way he's gonna do it.
也许是这样
Maybe not.
但是  路易  她是你家人
But, Louis, she's family,
要说有什么是哈维能理解的
and if there's one thing that Harvey understands,
那就是这个了
it's that.
你去哪里了
Where the hell have you been?
抱歉  路上堵死了
Sorry, I got stuck in really bad traffic.
你刚刚进错会议室了
So you were in the wrong conference room.
耽搁了差不多20分钟
For about 20 minutes.
和解金有多少
So what did we get?
想要猜猜看吗
Want to take a guess?
九千万
$90 million.
你还想认真猜猜吗
Want to take a real guess?
刚刚就是认真的啊
That was a real guess.
小子  你是哪个外星球来的
Son, what planet are you living on?
就是那个你管它叫
The planet where you called
"我们得到了很棒的和解协议"的星球
To say we got a great settlement.
两千五百万就是很棒的和解了
$25 million is a great settlement.
两千五百万
$25 million?
罗伯特  结完各种费用
Robert, after fees,
每个人连七万都拿不到
that's less than $70,000 per person.
那你觉得我们要如何回应
Then what do you suggest we counter with?
我建议上庭吧
I suggest we counter with a trial.
你疯了吗  不能上庭
Are you nuts? You don't go to trial.
只能给他们施压  然后和解
You turn up the pressure, and then you settle.
上庭就是施压啊
Going to trial is turning up the pressure.
我们一讲完开庭陈词
The second we finish opening arguments,
钱就会翻三倍了
that offer is gonna triple.
听着  过去六年来  我和这两个人
Look, I've sat across the table from these two
谈判过四次
four times in the last six years,
他们说这是能给的最高价时
and when they say this is their best offer,
那就是这样了
It's their best offer,
我们就要建议受害者接受
and we're recommending it.
随你怎么建议
Well, you can recommend whatever you want.
反正我是要建议他们拒绝的
I'm recommending we reject it.
不能给客户相互矛盾的建议
You don't give clients conflicting opinions.
我俩关起门来统一意见
You work it out behind closed doors.
也许那就是问题所在
Well, maybe that's the problem.
你想要关起门来做事
You want to do things behind closed doors.
而我却想做到诚信公开
I actually want to be honest.
注意你的态度  迈克
Hey, watch yourself, Mike.
你自己说
You tell me this,
假如事关劳拉或者瑞秋的性命
would $70,000 per person
你还会觉得每人七万
be a great settlement if we were talking
是很好的和解协议吗
about Laura's life or Rachel's?
你给我滚
You get out of here!
在你想清楚为什么
You don't come back
要建议受害者接受和解前别回来
until you wrap your head around recommending this offer.
还有  不许再用她们俩来反驳我
And don't you ever use them against me again!
别告诉我他也不在这里
Don't tell me he wasn't in here either.
之前在的
He was in here, all right.
怎么了  和解失败了吗
What happened? Did the settlement fall through?
没失败  但应该让它失败的
No, it didn't, but it should've.
他们给的和解金额很少
They gave us a shitty offer.
而罗伯特准备接受
Robert's ready to take it.
拜托  假如真有那么糟糕
Come on, if it's really that bad,
他怎么会接受
why would he take it?
因为他知道他的客户们会大发雷霆
Because he knows his clients will jump all over it
而这是简单的解决办法
and it's the easy way out.
所以你觉得罗伯特不关心他的客户吗
So you think Robert doesn't care about his clients?
看起来确实是这样的
It sure seems that way.
迈克  我来这里只有几个月
Mike, I've only been here a few months,
但关于罗伯特・赞恩你可以有种种说法
and there are a lot of things you can say about Robert Zane,
但你唯独不能说
but what you can't say is that
他不关心自己的客户
he doesn't care about his clients.
走开  路易
Go away, Louis.
我本来要走的  但那样我就无法告诉你
I would, but then I couldn't tell you
我要把那五千万的公司给你了
about the $50-million company I'm giving you.
你为什么要那么做
And why would you do that?
因为我想要弥补我俩之间小小的误会
'Cause I want to make up for our little misunderstanding.
我们之间没什么误会
We didn't have a misunderstanding.
你以前是抢我的钱
You went after my money,
所以假如你主动给我客户
so if you're giving me a client,
那就说明还有其他的误会
there's some other misunderstanding
但是你太懦弱而不敢告诉我
that you're too chickenshit to tell me about.
是我妹妹的公司
It's my sister's company.
我会把她这个客户给你
I'll give you her business.
而你只需解决她的离婚案
All you have to do is handle her divorce.
我不想要你妹妹这个客户
I don't want your sister's business.
给我出去
Now get out.
哈维  她是我的家人
Harvey, this is my family.
我妹妹  她从没求过我任何事
My sister, she...has never asked me for anything
一次都没
Her entire life, not once.
这是第一次  我不能让她失望
Now the one time she does, I just can't let her down.
路易  我不是离婚律师
Louis, I'm not a divorce attorney.
你什么时候在意过这种无关紧要的细节了
When has a shitty detail like that ever stopped you before?
好吧  但我有两个条件
All right, I'll do it, on two conditions.
第一  你绝对不许插手
First, you stay completely out of this case.
没问题  第二呢
Done. Second?
我想好了再告诉你
I'll let you know when I think of it.
我怎么确定你不会提什么不能忍的要求呢
How do I know it won't be something I can't stomach?
不能确定  这就是条件
You don't, but those are my two conditions.
好吧  哈维  成交
Okay, Harvey, you have a deal.
就一点
One thing.
答应我你不会跟埃斯特睡了
Promise me you won't sleep with Esther.
相信我  路易  我最不想做的事
Believe me, Louis, the last thing I want to do
就是和你妹妹睡
is sleep with your sister.
你同意就好
I'm glad you agree.
等材料都弄好了我再联系你
I'll let you know when the paperwork's finished.
我知道你还没有
I know you didn't wrap your head
对那份协议回心转意
around this deal in the last ten minutes,
所以你现在来我办公室做什么
So what are you still doing in my office?
你要是我你也会做的事
Exactly what you'd be doing in my place.
罗伯特  你说你认识那两个律师
Robert, I know you said that you know these two lawyers,
但我不认识
but I don't.
我需要亲眼看到他们的底线
I need to see for myself what they will or won't do.
你还想还价
And you still want to counter.
至少要试一试
I want to at least try.
但你不想一个人试
Except you don't want to go by yourself,
你希望我和你一起
You want me to go with you.
是的
Yes, I do.
因为你我都清楚  如果我们不一起去
Because you and I both know, if we don't go together,
根本就没有机会赢
we don't stand a chance.
我们怎样都没有机会赢
I know we don't stand a chance either way.
我去了也只是让自己出丑罢了
And if I do go, it makes me look like a fool.
罗伯特  在法院时是我让你免于出丑
Robert, I saved you from looking like a fool in that courtroom.
我帮了你一把
I came through for you.
现在请你也为我做同样的事
Now I'm asking you to come through for me on this.
你和瑞秋真是如出一辙
You and Rachel are peas in a pod.
难以置信她的公司竟然真的值五千万
Can't believe she's really worth $50 million.
真不敢相信你从没听说过她的公司
I can't believe you've never heard of her company.
我看上去像会买很多隔热垫的人吗
Do I look like I buy a lot of potholders?
她又不是只卖隔热垫
She doesn't just sell potholders.
她的品牌和玛莎・斯图尔特的一样有名
She has a brand like Martha Stewart.
著名家政公司创始人
我知道你觉得她很了不起
Look, I get that you think she's impressive,
但对我来说  她只是路易的妹妹
but to me, she's just Louis's sister,
光是这点  就是第二大噩耗
which, as far as I'm concerned, is strike number two.
第一大是什么
What's strike number one?
她是路易的妹妹这个事实
The fact that she's Louis's sister.
拜托  哈维  听着
Oh, come on, Harvey, listen.
你能不能认真对待这件事
Are you gonna take this seriously or not?
我来告诉你我的计划
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我走进去
I'm gonna go walk there.
握握那女人的肥手
I'm gonna shake this woman's meaty hand.
然后把案子早解决早了事
I'm gonna get this over with as quickly as possible.
是你
You?
这不是在逗我吧
You've got to be kidding me.
你们认识
You two know each other?
所以你不是来和州长见面的
So you weren't meeting the governor.
你还要坚持说自己放了市长鸽子吗
You're telling me you were really gonna blow off the mayor?
市长  你根本不认识市长
The mayor. You don't know the mayor.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry,
这位是很快要被我炒鱿鱼的助理律师
let me introduce my soon-to-be former associate.
瑞秋・赞恩
Rachel Zane.
埃斯特・艾丁斯坦
Esther Edelstein.
终于有幸一见
It's nice to finally meet the man
我久仰大名的男人
I've heard such good things about.
终于有幸一见
It's nice to meet the woman
我除了讹传什么也没听说过的女人了
I've obviously heard nothing but lies about.
讲正题吧
Let's get to it.
好
Yes.
我必须得问
I just have to know,
你们有一个是被领养的吗
were one of the two of you adopted?
这么多年来我都被问习惯了
I've been asking that for years.
出去
Hey. Get out.
靠
Shit.
大点声  自恋狂  会议室又不是图书馆
Come on, speak up, narcissist, it's not a freakin' library.
提醒我把会议室的墙
Reminder to thin the walls
改薄或是开个洞
in the conference room/ make a peephole.
你干什么呢
What do you think you're doing?
什么事
What happened?
我只是在检查隔音效果
Oh, I was just checking the sound-proofing,
确保他们把会议室的墙加厚了
making sure they thicken the walls in the conference room.
所以我出门右转的话
So if I walk out this door and I turn to the right,
不会看见哈维和埃斯特在会议室里吗
I won't see Harvey in there with Esther?
埃斯特来了  我都不知道
Esther's here? I didn't know that.
路易  隔墙偷听
Louis, listening through the wall
可不叫不插手她的案子
is not staying out of her case,
如果被哈维发现了  他会放弃她的案子的
and if Harvey finds out, he's gonna drop her.
那可是我妹妹
Look, it's my sister, all right?
我只想确保他不含私心地对待她
I just want to make sure he does right by her.
如果你不相信他的人品的话
And you never would have asked him to take this case
你就不会请他接这个案子了
if you didn't trust that he would do just that.
所以  把杯子放下  回你办公室去
So put the glass down, go back to your office,
让他做他的工作就好
and let him do his job.
你要是时不时出点错
You know it'd be easier for both of us
我俩都能好过点
if you were wrong every once in a while.
我们决定离婚时  我和杰弗里达成共识
When we decided to get divorced, Jeffrey and I agreed
他会得到20%的公司股份  不用请律师
he would get 20% of the company, no need to involve lawyers.
接下来  我却收到一封律师函
The next thing I knew, I got a letter from a lawyer.
杰弗里觉得20%不够了
Jeffrey doesn't think 20% is enough anymore.
没错
No, he doesn't.
埃斯特  我要问你个问题
Esther, I'm gonna ask you a question,
希望你诚实地回答我
and I want you to answer me honestly.
是谁要离开谁
Who's leaving who?
我们都想离
It's mutual.
从没有双方都想离的
It's never mutual.
所以我再问一遍  是谁主动要离婚的
So I'm gonna ask you again. Who's driving this decision?
我
I am.
那我们解决问题的方法
Then the answer to our problem
就是让你不参与谈判
is for you to stay away from the negotiations.
什么  不行  我得参与
What? No, I'm not staying away.
听我说
Listen to me.
他背弃你们的协议
He's going back on your deal
是因为他想拖长这场战斗
because he wants to prolong the fight.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我花了12年建立起公司
I spent 12 years building the company.
我不会袖手旁观  让别人替我决定
I'm not gonna sit back and let someone else decide
能给我剩下多少
how much I'm allowed to keep.
那你还来找我干什么
Then what'd you come to me for?
因为你是最好的律师
Because you're supposed to be the best.
我是最好的  但我的风格
I am the best, and I didn't get that way
可不是让别人做决定
letting someone else call the shots.
所以你要么让我全权接手
So you're either gonna let me do that,
要么就换个律师吧
or you're gonna get yourself another lawyer.
我需要你做这些事
All right, here's what I need you to do.
你可以一分钟后再告诉我要干什么
You can tell me what you need me to do in a minute.
首先我们讨论刚刚发生的事
First we're gonna talk about what happened back there.
刚刚发生的是  我亮明规矩
What happened is, I laid down the law,
她接受了  我是大哥
she accepted, I'm the man.
是啊
Yep, uh-huh.
但我要说的不是那个
Okay, I'm not talking about that.
我想说的是你进门那一瞬间
I'm talking about how the moment you walked through the door,
就像被闪电劈了一样
you looked like you were struck by a bolt of lighting.
-我才没有  -绝对有
- I did not. - You most certainly did.
其实在你开始正事之前
In fact, before you started fighting,
我都担心你俩会在桌上来一炮
I was afraid the two of you were gonna go at it on the table.
担心还是希望
Afraid or hoping?
真恶心
That's unsavory.
对我们的客户发表下流评论就不恶心吗
And you making lewd comments about our client isn't?
哪个客户的下流评论
Lewd comments about what client?
哈维喜欢路易的妹妹
Harvey likes Louis's sister.
巧了  我来找他就是为了
That's funny, 'cause that's exactly what I came in here
谈这件事
to talk to him about.
你也喜欢路易的妹妹
You like Louis's sister?
还没喜欢到跟你争
Not enough to fight you for her.
你该重新考虑一下  她很可爱
Well, you should reconsider. She's lovely.
我先走了
And I'm leaving.
哈维  为什么突然之间
Harvey, why are you all of a sudden
埃斯特・艾丁斯坦成了你的客户
taking on Esther Edelstein as a client?
你可别告诉我因为她可爱
And don't tell me it's because she's lovely,
我可不相信
because I'm not sure I believe that.
路易求我  我才接了她的案子
I took her on because Louis asked me to.
可是上次我还听说  我们都在生他的气呢
And the last I heard, you and I were both pissed at him.
我的气没消啊
And I still am.
但他告诉我这是他的家人
But he told me this was family,
而且  我觉得这也是个机会
and...I thought this might be a chance
让我们重回正轨
for us all to get back on track.
干得不错  哈维
I like that, Harvey.
最后发现
You just might turn out
你还算是半个合格的冠名合伙人啊
to be a half decent name partner after all.
我深表怀疑
I doubt it.
我也不确定
So do I.
坦白说  罗伯特  我很惊讶
Well, frankly, Robert, I'm surprised
你竟然又要开会
you called for another meeting.
被例行还价吓到了吗
Surprised by a routine counter?
确实  尤其是我们的第一个提议那么大方
When the first offer is as generous as ours, I am.
听他把话说完  威尔
Just hear the man out, Will.
坎贝尔诉国家健康公司案
Campbell v. State health.
威尔逊诉健力医疗案
Wilson v. GenRx.
弗莱德曼诉领先医疗公司案
Friedman v. Medfirst.
这些集体诉讼案都差不多
Those are identical class actions
它们的赔偿金额是
in which the average payout
平均每位原告50万
was $1/2 million per plaintiff.
这是法庭裁决的结果  其中还有两个因为
They were jury awards, and two of them were reduced
过度惩罚而降低了金额
for being excessively punitive.
那最后的金额也比你们给的高
Dollar amount was still higher than what's on the table.
可人家打了7年的官司呢
After seven years of appeals.
没错  可是我们也说了  不在乎时间
Yeah, and like we said, we don't care how long it takes.
我们希望你们现在给的金额能再翻三倍
We want triple what you're offering.
我还想跟索菲娅・维加拉一起裸泳呢
And I want to skinny dip with Sofia Vergara,
但是  臣妾做不到啊
But no puedo hacerlo.
这句西班牙语是说"我们连一分钱都不会再多给"
That's Spanish for "We're not giving you another nickel."
那西班牙语的"法庭见"怎么说
And what's Spanish for "We'll see you in court"?
放马过来
Bring it on.
好了  威尔  别动气
That's enough. Come on, Will.
我们这不还在谈嘛
We're just having a conversation.
谈
Conversation?
罗伯特  我给了你一个很好的提议
I gave you a fair offer, Robert,
因为我尊重你
because I respect you,
我觉得你也是尊重我的  所以当我说这是
and I thought that you respected me enough to know
我能争取到的最好结果时  我以为你会懂
that I meant it when I said it's the best I could do.
结果他就过来  威胁我说要上法庭
Then he comes in here threatening a trial.
现在好了
Well, you know what?
你要是看不上我们给的价
You don't like what's on the table,
那我们就统统撤回
we can pull the whole damn thing.
跟你说了他不是在开玩笑的
I told you he wasn't messing around.
你说对了
You were right about that.
但是上法庭这个决定也是对的
Now I'm right about taking this to trial.
你什么也没说对
You aren't right about anything.
我欠你的  我还过了  我们结束了
I owed you. I paid up. We're done.
不  我们没完  我还是不会
No, we're not done, and I'm still not
推荐我的客户接受这个提议
recommending this offer to my clients.
那真是太可惜了  他们已经签掉了
Well, that's too bad, because they already signed off.
什么
What?
我们来之前你就跟客户通过气了
You talked to our clients before we even went in there?
是的
You're damn right I did.
我们已经试过了  没用
We took a shot, and it didn't work.
现在呢  我们有义务
Now, in the meantime, we had an obligation
把他们的提议告诉客户  所以我就这么做了
to show their offer to our clients, and I did.
别给我在这儿扯他妈的淡
Don't give me some bullshit justification.
你背着我做事
You went behind my back.
我没背着你做事  我是越过你做事
I didn't go behind your back. I went over your head.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你知道我说的是什么
You know what the hell I'm talking about.
我去找了你老板的老板  你知道吗
I went to your boss's boss, and you know what?
她跟我的看法是一样的
She and I see things the same way.
从我的角度来看  这个案子已经结束了
And as far as I'm concerned, this case is settled.
二位请坐  我们马上开始
Why don't you two have a seat? I suggest we get right to it.
等一下  埃斯特呢
Wait a second, where's Esther?
她不来了  由我全权代表她
She won't be joining us, but I've been authorized
来进行谈判
to negotiate on her behalf.
不  不行  她不来我什么都不会同意的
No. No, I'm not agreeing to anything without her here.
那是因为你不是真心来谈判的
That's because you don't really want to negotiate,
你只是还想和她有所联系
you just want to stay connected to her,
但这是不可能的
and that's not gonna happen.
我不知道你是什么时候转做离婚律师的
I don't know when you decided to become a divorce attorney,
但这事儿不是这么干的
but that's not how it works.
我没转做离婚律师
I didn't become a divorce attorney
因为这只是小打小闹罢了
because it's the minor leagues,
但这就是我做事的方式
but this is how it works with me.
这是什么鬼
What the hell is this?
我们的新方案  什么都不给你
That's our new offer, nothing.
太扯了
This is bullshit.
你认为你该分得
You thinking you deserve even 20%
我们客户公司的20%才是胡扯
of our client's business is bullshit.
所以  你要么接受
So you're either gonna accept the terms that
你和埃斯特先前的条款
you and Esther agreed to,
要么接受我们的新方案
or you can take our new offer.
随你们怎么威胁
You can threaten all you want,
但我的客户有权分得属于他的财产
but my client has a right to what's his,
也就是公司的一半
and that's half the company,
因为这是十二年前  你的客户答应过的
because 12 years ago, that's what your client agreed to.
我当时不仅要成为埃斯特的丈夫
See, I wasn't just gonna be Esther's husband.
我还要当医生
I was gonna be a doctor,
但埃斯特的公司刚起步
but I put that on hold
我就搁置了这个计划
while Esther got her company off the ground,
我跟她说了我的想法后
and when I said I was willing to do that,
她说会把公司分我一半
she said I'd get half.
这构成了强制性口头契约
Which constitutes an enforceable verbal contract.
我不在乎埃斯特在不在
So I don't care whether Esther's here or not.
她承诺与我共度一生
She promised to spend our lives together,
现在她要违背那个诺言
and she's breaking that promise.
对于这点  我无计可施
There's nothing I can do about that one,
但我非常确定  我会让她遵守另一个承诺
but I'm sure as hell gonna hold her to the other one.
你没有证据证明她许下过这样的承诺
You have no proof she ever made that promise.
去问你的客户吧
Ask your client about it,
当她宣誓作证的时候
because when we depose her under oath,
我们一定会问她
you can rest assured we will.
是你批准了和解方案
You authorized the settlement?
能好好说话吗
You want to change that tone?
不  不能  你让罗伯特・赞恩
No, I don't, because you told Robert Zane
把我当合伙人
to treat me like a partner,
可你回过身来  又对我捆手捆脚
and then you turned around, and you cut my legs out.
我那么说  是因为你是我的代表
I told him that because you were my proxy,
可你对我没尽到代理义务
but you're not my proxy with me.
我不喜欢我的决定被质疑
And I don't appreciate my decisions being questioned.
你看过那他们的协议吗
Did you even look at that offer?
迈克  我要跟你解释一下
Mike, I'm going to explain something to you
你既然这么气势汹汹来找我
that, based on your approach to this conversation,
显然还不明白
you clearly don't understand.
开庭将花费数百万
This trial will cost millions.
阿卡迪亚基金有的是钱
And Arcadian has deep pockets.
那他们也不会找着拿钱去冒险
And they're not looking to empty them on a gamble.
所以都是因为钱
So this is all just about the money.
你是三岁小孩吗
Were you born yesterday?
客户要的是钱
The clients are looking for money.
我们要赚钱
We're looking for money.
保险公司想要保住钱
The insurance company's looking to keep money.
永远都是钱的事
It's always about the money.
如果你有点种  我们会赚多得多的钱
And if you had some balls, we'd get a whole lot more.
听好了  我不知道你觉得跑来找我
Listen to me, I don't know what you thought marching in here
除了惹我生气还能有什么用
was going to do other than piss me off,
但你给我从哪来回哪去
but you're going to march the hell back out
比起跟你解释普世真理
because I have better things to do with my time
我有更重要的事要做
than to explain to you how the world works.
我收到你的消息了
Hey, I got your message.
杰弗里签协议了吗
Jeffrey signed the agreement?
签了
He did.
只差你的签名了
All it needs is your John Hancock.
等等  这不是20%  是50%
Wait, this doesn't say 20%. It says 50%.
抱歉  我是不是忘了说
Oh, I'm sorry, did I forget to mention
他说你曾答应把公司分他一半
that he said you promised him 50% of your company
因为他推迟了上医学院的计划
for putting off medical school?
因为很显然  你忘了告诉我
Because you sure forgot to mention that to me.
你在开玩笑吧
You have got to be kidding me.
你怎么能不告诉我呢
How could you not tell me that?
因为这只是十二年前
Because it was a throwaway conversation
我们在新泽西高速路上开车时随口一说
we had 12 years ago on the New Jersey turnpike.
他可不觉得是随口一说  他会利用这点
Well, it wasn't throwaway to him, and he's gonna use it
因为他觉得自己被背叛了
because he's feeling betrayed.
我才不在乎他的感受
Well, I don't really care what he's feeling
搞外遇的是他又不是我
because he's the one who had the affair.
你想知道我们为什么离婚
You wanted to know the circumstances of our divorce.
这就是理由
Well, that's what they are.
所以我才想离开他
That's why I'm leaving him.
我知道你不会明白
I am sure you wouldn't understand what's it like
爱人不忠是什么感受
to experience infidelity.
我明白  我也知道
I would, and I do,
但这不能改变你许下口头契约的事实
but that doesn't change the fact that you made a contract.
另一份合同怎么算  20%那份
What about our other contract? 20%.
原始协议优先级更高
The original agreement supersedes it,
出轨也不能改变
and an affair doesn't change that.
但他没有证据
Except he doesn't have any proof
我当初和他有过这一协议
I ever made the original agreement.
埃斯特  他们会让你宣誓作证
Esther, they're gonna put you under oath
然后直接问你  你们有没有这一协议
and ask you point-blank if this happened.
那我就说没有
And I'm going to say it didn't.
那是作伪证  我不能让你那样做
That's perjury, and I'm not gonna let you do that.
你以为你是谁
What are you,
一个从来不会为了赢而越线的光明骑士吗
some white knight who never crosses the line to win?
不  但我不会让你
No, but I'm not gonna let you make a decision
一时头脑发热
in the heat of the moment
做出会令你后悔终身的决定
that you'll regret for the rest of your life.
那你最好找到别的办法让这份协议失效
Well, then you better find some other way to void this deal,
因为我绝不可能让我那混蛋丈夫
because there's no way I'm giving my shit bag husband
拿走我的一半财产
half of everything I own.
我需要你找出口头合约的
I need you to find every loophole there is
所有可能漏洞
around verbal contracts.
所以杰弗里说的是实话
So Jeffrey was telling the truth?
是的  而她宁死也不愿意
Yes, and she'd rather slit her wrists
给他一半财产  而且我不怪她
than give him 50%, and I don't blame her.
但是她主动提出离婚的  所以...
Yeah, but she's the one who's leaving him, so--
他搞外遇了  是吗
He cheated on her, didn't he?
那是我们的委托人
Well, that's between our client
和她准前夫之间的事
and her soon-to-be ex-husband,
反正我绝不会让他
and I have no intention of letting him
就这样占她便宜的
get the better of her.
怎么了
What?
这激起了你的保护欲  很贴心
You're being protective. It's sweet.
听我说  我们保护埃斯特
Okay, listen to me, we're protecting Esther
是因为这就是我们的职责
because it's our job to protect her.
如果我们想不出办法解决这件事
And if we don't figure a way out of this,
她就会损失数百万美元
she's gonna lose millions of dollars,
所以你想要观察我们两个的事  随便你
so you want to make observations about the two of us,
但要等我们赢了以后
do it all you want after we've won.
我马上去做
I'm on it.
好了  这是最终协议备忘  这是核准授权
Okay, so final deal memos here, check authorizations here.
现在只要让凯尔顿签完字  我们就完事了
Now all we need to do is get Kelton to sign, and we are done.
迈克  我知道你认为这个协议烂透了
Mike, I know you think this deal sucks,
但毕竟还有好的一面
but there is a silver lining.
我们又能一起工作了
we got to work together again.
怎么了
What?
我只是回想起我们刚认识的时候
I was just thinking about when we started.
谁会想到和你一起工作
Who would've thought that working with you
会是好的一面
would ever have been a silver lining?
我
Me?
是啊  你
Yeah, you.
你就好到哪去吗
What about you?
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我从一开始就一直很友善的
I have been a gentleman since day one.
-真的吗  -当然
- Really? - Yes.
你不记得飞机那件事了吗
Remember the whole airplane incident?
我记得吗  当然记得  是你...
Do I? Yes, you were the one who--
等等  等等等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
等一下  达美金融
Wait a second. Delta Financial.
他们怎么了
What about them?
罗伯特・赞恩的桌子上有一本
There was a brochure for Delta Bauer Financial
达美-鲍尔金融的手册
on Robert Zane's desk.
上面说明  他们是
And on top of that, they were listed
阿卡迪亚基金的一家子公司
as a subsidiary on Arcadian's annual report.
他们的子基金公司多着呢
As are 50 other funds.
可是其它基金公司的手册
50 other funds that don't have a brochure
都没有出现在罗伯特・赞恩的桌子上
on Robert Zane's desk.
-迈克  -卡特里娜
- Mike-- - Katrina,
我需要知道他们是不是你们的客户
I need to know if they're one of your clients.
你明知道我不能告诉你
You know I can't tell you that.
那就说明是了
Okay, well, you just did.
我还需要知道他们是不是拥有凯尔顿的股份
Now I need to know if they own shares of Kelton.
我不知道他们有没有股份  我也不会去查
I don't know if they own shares, and I'm not gonna find out.
你不在乎罗伯特・赞恩为了一家对冲基金受益
You don't care if Robert Zane is manipulating a case
而操纵一个案子吗
to service a hedge fund?
我在不在乎无所谓
It doesn't matter if I care.
我不能违反律师委托人保密协议
I can't violate attorney-client privilege.
你说你欠我一个人情
You said you owe me.
而你说我其实是欠瑞秋的
And you said I owe Rachel.
卡特里娜  拜托
Katrina, please.
你说罗伯特一定会为委托人的利益着想
You said that Robert is doing right by his clients.
我需要知道他在为哪个委托人的利益着想
Well, I just need to know which clients he's doing right by.
你有时间吗
Do you have a minute?
我上次这样问你的时候  你告诉我说没时间
The last time I asked you that, you told me the answer was no.
然后我还是花时间听你说话了
And I still gave you the minute.
我正好在忙着
Well, I happen to be in the middle
收拾路易妹妹的烂摊子  所以
of trying to get Louis's sister out of a huge mess, so--
我就是想和你谈这个
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
路易答应不会插手的
Louis promised to stay out of this.
没他的事  我不是他派来的
And he is, and I'm not here because he asked me to be.
我来是因为我在乎他
I'm here because I care about him and--
这跟我没关系
That's not my problem.
哈维  我不是你的敌人
Harvey, I'm not the enemy here.
而路易是你的合作伙伴和朋友
And Louis is your partner and your friend,
现在  他需要一颗定心丸
And right now, he needs a little reassurance.
我告诉过你了  我不是
And I told you before, I'm not the guy
那个会在你害怕时给你一个拥抱的人
That gives you a hug when you're scared.
我是在你最需要的时候能帮助你取胜的人
I'm the guy that wins when you need it the most.
你为什么就不能
Why can't you for once--
你知道吗  唐娜  我向你求助的时候
You know what, donna, when I came to you for help,
你说我没有资格再那么做了
You said that I don't get to do that anymore.
你现在也没有资格这么做了
Well, you don't get to do this anymore.
现在  请原谅  我还有事要做
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have work to do.
你知道吗  哈维
You know what, Harvey?
路易本来不敢让你接手这个案子
Louis was afraid to let you take this case,
我让他别担心  因为我相信
And I told him not to be because I trusted
最终
that at the end of the day,
你会记得我们是一家人
You'd remember that we're family.
但也许我错了
But maybe I was wrong.
因为十二年来  我都把你放在第一位
Because I spent 12 years putting you first,
我终于决定为自己做些事情的时候
and the day I finally decided to do something for myself,
你不止不再把我当家人
You didn't just stop treating me like family,
你开始把我当陌生人
You started treating me like a stranger.
而这比把我当做敌人
And for your information, that is a thousand times worse
还要伤人一千倍
Than if you treated me like your enemy.
路易  你有什么事吗
Louis, did you need something?
我想让你知道我为你骄傲
I need you to know how proud I am of you,
看到你这样努力工作
'cause seeing you working like this
使我想起了你如何为法学院入学考试奋战
Just reminds me how you persevered with the LSATs,
如何进入了法学院  而现在
and how you got into law school, and now--
路易  我是不会向你透露埃斯特案子的情况的
Louis, I'm not telling you about Esther's case.
那要你还有什么用
Well, then what the hell good are you?
路易  你答应过哈维  不会插手的
Louis, you promised Harvey you would stay out of it.
我只是想知道发生了什么
I just need to know what happened.
什么发生了什么
What happened with what?
他们之间怎么了
What happened with them.
我恨杰弗里不是秘密
I mean, it's no secret that I hated Jeffrey,
但埃斯特  她爱他
But Esther, she loved him,
他们就这样
and for them to just--
我得知道为什么
I need to know why.
他有外遇了
He cheated on her.
那你答应我  你们两个
Well, then you promise me that the two of you...
不要放过那个混蛋
stick it to that sack of shit.
你觉得我在做什么呢
What do you think I'm working on?
文书什么的都搞定了吗
We're all squared away on the paperwork?
在你告诉我你是否知情之前
No, we're not squared away on shit
我们屁都没搞定
until you tell me whether or not you knew.
你敢再说一遍吗
You want to run that by me again?
达美金融  你的客户
Delta Financial, your client.
你知道他们巨额投资了凯尔顿保险公司吗
Did you know they were heavily invested in Kelton?
你在指控我做了什么吗
Are you accusing me of something, Mike?
你最好注意你的言辞
Because you better watch what you say.
你还是没回答我的问题
You still haven't answered my question.
你知道资助我们的对冲基金的子公司
Did you know a subsidiary of the hedge fund
刚刚购入了大量凯尔顿保险公司的股份吗
backing our suit just purchased a huge block of Kelton shares?
我是他们的律师  不是证券分析师
I am their lawyer, not a stock analyst.
那你或许可以解释一下
Then maybe you can explain to me
为什么你桌上有一本他们的宣传册
why you have one of their brochures on your desk?
听着  过目不忘小子
Okay, listen to me, Mr. Photographic memory.
在这本宣传册下面是另外
Underneath this brochure are another 35
35本堆了一年半的册子
that have been piling up there for a year and a half
因为我打算进行投资
Because I'm looking to invest my money
而这笔钱有一天会属于你们的孩子
that someday may be going to your children.
你以为我们想要你通过将和解金额
Wait, you think we want money that comes from some stock
压到低于正常预期而使股票暴涨
that went through the roof because you authorized
得到的钱吗
a settlement lower than street expectations?
好的  你说完了  现在该我说了
Okay, you've said your piece. Now I'm gonna say mine.
你出生前我就开始
I have been a lawyer and an officer of the court
做律师和法院人员了
longer than you've breathed air,
我现在看着你的眼睛
and I'm looking you straight in the eye
告诉你我是个正直的人
and telling you that I am an honest man.
作为一个正直的人
You know as an honest man
你应该知道我们发现了这个
that now that we've discovered this,
由于利益冲突我们必须披露它
we have to disclose it as conflict of interest.
那就用超小号字体把它埋在文件里
Then bury it, deep in the fine print,
因为我给出的建议与它无关
because it had nothing to do with my recommendation,
我不会让它毁了这次交易
and I'm not gonna let it blow this goddamn deal.
这什么时候成了一次取证会
Since when did this become a deposition?
原本不是  但你似乎急着逼问埃斯特
It didn't, but since you seemed so anxious to ask Esther
她以前说过的话
about what she said in the past,
我想我可以给大家省省力气
I thought I'd just save us all the trouble
亲自把取证给做了
and get it on the record myself.
什么  我从没同意过...
What? I never agreed--
你承诺过要给杰弗里公司的一半  是吗
You promised Jeffrey 50% of your company, didn't you?
没错
Yes, I did.
这不就结了
Then it's settled.
还没呢
Well, not quite.
既然我们的委托人
Now that our client has admitted
承认了那个协议
that she made the agreement,
我们想谈谈她许下承诺时
we'd like to discuss the circumstances
她所处的情况
under which she did.
你说情况是什么意思
What do you mean the circumstances?
她答应给我50%  就是这样
She promised me 50%, period.
不  她答应给你50%是因为你放弃了
No, she promised you 50% because you forfeited
读医学院的机会
your admission to medical school.
没错  我放弃了去斯坦福
That's right, and instead of going to Stanford,
留在家里照顾家庭
I stayed home and took care of our family.
那么为什么没有任何
Then why is there no record of you
斯坦福录取你的记录呢
ever being admitted to Stanford?
其他学校的录取记录也没有
Or any school, for that matter?
只有一叠拒信
Just a pile of rejection letters.
你骗我
You lied to me?
荒唐
This is ridiculous.
很多人都不是第一次
Lots of people don't get into medical school
就能申请到上医学院的
on the first try.
你第一次就想把我半个公司抢走
You were gonna take half of my company on the first try.
30%
30%.
他休想从我亲手建立的公司
He's not getting another penny
再拿走一毛钱
of the business I built myself.
你想说你拥有的这一切都是靠你自己
You want to talk about doing things yourself?
那是谁在你忙着烤松饼
Who do you think stayed home and kept our family together
忙到没时间给孩子做晚餐时
while you were too busy baking muffins
留在家里稳固家庭
to make dinner for your kids?
你别拿母亲职责来说我
Don't you dare attack me as a mother!
是你对我不忠
You cheated on me!
埃斯特  对不起
Esther, I'm sorry.
我的确做了错事
I made a mistake.
但我确实为你放弃了一切
But I did give up everything for you.
我暂停了自己的人生追求
I put my life on hold.
为了成全你的梦想放弃了自己的
I sacrificed my dream for yours.
我不可能再追回逝去的岁月了
I'm never gonna get those years back.
不  杰弗里
No, Jeffrey.
我们曾经拥有一切
We had everything,
是你把这一切都毁了
and you ruined it.
行了  可以了
All right, that's enough.
我们最终报价你们已经拿到了
You have our final offer.
这次最好别再是罗伯特・赞恩的事
This better not be about Robert Zane again.
-给我一分钟就好  -见鬼
- Just give me one minute. - God damn it.
他有一个客户买了凯尔顿的股份
One of his clients purchased shares of Kelton,
如果他们按保密信息处理...
and if they acted on privileged information--
我懂法律
I know the law.
那你知道这么做轻则违反职业道德
Well, then you know it's unethical at best
重则违反法律
and illegal at worst.
你要我怎么做
What do you want from me?
我知道你觉得他是否事前知晓
I want to know if you think he knew.
这有什么分别
What the hell difference does that make?
区别在于这算合法结案
It's the difference between a legitimate settlement
还是股价操纵
and stock manipulation.
你是说这会让他变成诈骗犯
You mean it would make him a fraud?
这是两码事  你知道
This isn't the same thing, and you know it.
我不想让玩弄我的委托人
I'm not trying to screw over my clients.
你为什么要提起那茬
Why would you even bring that up right now?
因为你当初求我接这个案子
Because you begged me for this case
还要和那个人合作
and a chance to work with that man.
如果他和保险公司勾结
And if he colluded with them,
我们可以逼他们给更高的赔偿
we can stick a better settlement down their throats.
你真觉得罗伯特・赞恩会卑鄙到做那种事
Do you really think Robert Zane is dirty enough to do that?
我不知道  但我很难相信
I don't know, but I find it hard to believe
他会愚钝到忽略此事
that he's dumb enough not to know.
我爸爸才不蠢
My dad's not dumb.
-也不卑鄙  -瑞秋
- And he's not dirty. - Rachel...
上次路易说他阴险
And the last time someone called him shady,
你还几乎要举拳打他
it was Louis, and you almost punched him over it.
这是两码事
This is different.
就是一码事
This is the same.
你要打他是因为侮辱我
You were gonna punch him because an attack on me
就是侮辱你
is an attack on you.
现在我说侮辱我父亲就是侮辱我
Well, attack on my father is an attack on me,
而做这件事的人正是你
and you're the one who's doing it.
我没有侮辱谁
Nobody's attacking anybody.
迈克  你曾经
Mike, you once came to me
要求我不要轻易对你下定论
asking me to give you the benefit of the doubt,
我给了你机会
and I gave it to you.
所以你至少也该给他机会
So the least you can do is give it to him.
我本来期待你能给我好消息呢
I was hoping you had good news,
但你在这儿自斟自饮好像不是因为成交了
but you're not pouring that drink because we have a deal.
是还没成交  但也可以成交了
We don't, but we can.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我的意思是他们要求30%
I'm saying they offered 30%,
我谈到了25%
and I talked them down to 25%.
我凭什么接受25%
And why should I take it?
因为纠缠不放已经不再是他了
Because he's not the one dragging this fight out anymore.
是你
You are.
而且不管你相不相信
And whether or not you believe
他为你放弃了一切  这都是事实
he gave up everything for you, he does.
我难道没权利生气吗
Tell me I don't have the right to be angry.
你知道我为什么根本不考虑
Do you know why I never even considered
做离婚律师吗
becoming a divorce attorney?
大材小用吗
Because it's beneath you.
因为牵涉到孩子
Because there are children involved.
当人们陷入离婚的泥潭
When people get caught up in divorce...
就会忘记生活中其实还有
they forget there are some things in life
比金钱重要的东西
that are more important than money.
好吧  哈维
Okay, Harvey.
25%
25%.
我得说  你和我想象的哈维・斯佩克特
You know, you're not exactly
不太一样呢
the Harvey Specter I was expecting.
这是好事还是坏事
Is that a good thing or a bad thing?
好事
A good thing.
你和我对路易妹妹的想象也相去甚远
You're not exactly the louis's sister I was expecting.
这又是好事还是坏事
Is that a good thing or a bad thing?
好事  绝对是好事
A good thing. Definitely a good thing.
今晚你还愿意带我回家吗
Would you like to take me home tonight?
愿意
I would.
但你得先把这个签了
But I need you to sign that first.
为什么
Why is that?
因为签了之后你就不是我的委托人了
Because then you won't be my client anymore.
很有原则嘛
A man with a code.
你可能还真是个光明骑士
Maybe you are a white knight after all.
行了  我们走吧
Come on, let's get out of here.
路易  大半夜的  你到底
Louis, it's midnight. What's--
哈维坑了埃斯特
Harvey's screwing Esther.
-什么  -你看
- What? - Look at this.
这是埃斯特签的协议
It's an agreement that Esther signed
同意给杰弗里25%
that agrees to give Jeffrey 25%.
这比她答应给那混蛋的多了5%
That's 5% more than she needs to pay that son of a bitch.
你在哪看到的
Where did you get this?
我走在走廊里
Well, I was walking down the hall.
看到两个杯子一瓶威士忌  还有这个
I saw two glasses, a bottle of scotch, and that.
他灌醉了她  以此报复我
He got her drunk, so he could screw me over.
哈维绝不会干这种事的
Okay, there is no way Harvey would ever do that.
你大半夜吵醒我就为了说这个啊
You woke me up in the middle of the night to tell me that?
唐娜  多给5%就是三百万
Donna, 5% extra is $3 million.
你怎么解释这个
How do you explain that?
-解释不了  -我来解释
- I can't. - I can.
他是要借坑我家人来报复我
He's trying to get me back about his compensation
为他酬金的事
by trying to screw over another litt.
所以我需要你
So what I need you to do--
路易  我需要做的唯一一件事
Louis, the only thing that I need to do
就是告诉你你疯了  然后回屋睡觉
is tell you you're crazy and go back to sleep.
如果到明早之前  除当面质问哈维之外
And if you do anything between now and tomorrow
你做了任何事  我发誓
other than confront Harvey face-to-face, so help me God,
你明天一早就没有秘书了
you will not have a secretary in the morning.
我打算放下这件事了
I'm letting it go.
这和你
Does that have something to do
一大早去的地方有关吗
with where you've been so early in the morning?
有
Yeah.
你去见我爸爸了
You went to see my dad?
我去见艾玛・鲍尔了
I went to see Emma Powell,
问她对协议的看法
asked her how she felt about the settlement.
她说这会改变她的生活
She said it would change her life.
你就跟她说钱给少了
You said it wasn't enough money.
她都没提钱的事
She didn't even mention the money.
她说对她来说  这个结果证明了
She said, for her, the settlement was proof
凯尔顿在她丈夫的事情上有过错
that Kelton didn't do right by her husband,
而那是她唯一需要的
and that was all she needed.
好吧
Okay.
所以就因为原告满意了
So because the plaintiff was happy,
突然之间  你就觉得我爸爸是个诚实的人了
all of a sudden, you think my dad's an honest man.
不是
No.
我去是为了看能不能让这事过去
I went there to see if I could let it go.
我知道你爸爸是个诚实的人
I know your dad is an honest man
因为他养成了你这样的女儿
because he's raised someone like you.
你说得对
You were right.
我不该质疑他的正直
I never should have questioned his integrity.
我还有一点也是对的
I was also right
你就不该接这个案子
that you never should've taken this case.
不  那件事你错了
No, you were wrong about that.
我跟你说过  我们可能会吵架
I told you we might fight,
但那会让我们更亲密
but it would bring us closer together,
那也确实实现了
and it did.
不仅是我跟你爸爸
And not just me and your father.
你指什么
What does that mean?
还有你跟你爸爸
I mean you and your father.
我从没见过你那样毫不犹豫地维护他
I have never seen you leap to his defense like that.
我毫不犹豫地维护他  有吗
I did leap to his defense, didn't I?
当然有
You sure did.
你觉得我们的女儿会毫不犹豫地维护我吗
You think our daughter will leap to my defense
某天  像你一样
like that one day?
她会的
She sure will.
路易  你在这里做什么
Louis, what are you doing here?
我来告诉你我在做什么
I'll tell you what I'm doing here.
我来当面跟你谈你坑了我妹妹的事
I'm coming to you face-to-face about screwing my sister.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我看了条款  哈维  简直开玩笑
I saw the terms, Harvey. They're a joke.
不  那些是埃斯特想要的
No, they're what Esther wanted.
而你发过誓  不管这事
And you swore you'd stay out of this.
我没管真是好事
Well, it's a good thing I didn't
因为她不可能想要送掉
because there's no way she wanted to give away
几百万美元
millions of dollars.
那叫退一步海阔天空
It's called being charitable in order to move on.
那叫杰弗里是堆垃圾
It's called Jeffrey's a piece of shit,
他又不是优生优育基金会
not the March of Dimes.
他什么都不该得
He should be getting nothing.
与其关注他得到了什么
Instead of being focused on what he gets,
你不如看看埃斯特得到了什么
you should be focused on what Esther gets,
她很开心
which is to be happy.
错了  利特家的人从不会开心
Wrong, Litts are never happy,
而你在利用她伤害我
and you're using her to get to me.
我要怎么才能用这办法伤到你呢
How the hell am I doing that?
你觉得我利用
You think I went after your money
调整律所薪资结构来抢你的钱
by changing the firm's compensation structure.
你是抢了我的钱
You did come after my money!
现在你在抢埃斯特的钱来扳回一局
And now you're going after Esther's to even the score.
我要想扳回一局
If I wanted to even the score,
是不会去找你妹妹的
I wouldn't come after your sister.
我会找你
I'd be coming after you.
你听好了
And for your information,
我之所以能说服她选择原谅
I convinced her to be forgiving by telling her
是因为我告诉她
that there are some things in life
世上有很多事比钱重要
that are more important than money.
胡说  这话你自己都不相信
Bullshit! You don't believe that.
路易  我没想做这事报复你
Louis, I didn't take this to get back at you.
我做这事是因为这是我们停战
I took it because it was a chance to bury the hatchet
然后往前走的机会
and move on.
所以你要么让那些条款生效
So either let these terms stand,
要么就像你平时一样  搞砸一切
or do what you always do and screw everything up.
罗伯特  我很高兴你来了
Robert, I'm glad you're here--
你做了什么
What the hell did you do?
你指的是什么
What are you talking about?
我去见了艾玛・鲍尔
I went to see Emma Powell,
但我发誓  我没有破坏和解
But I swear to god, I did not undermine the settlement.
我不是说那个
I'm not talking about that.
我在说你背着我去找阿卡迪亚基金
I'm talking about you going behind my back to Arcadian.
我没去
I didn't do that.
在你上次跟我说了那些之后
Oh, you expect me to believe that
你还指望我相信你吗
after all the shit you told me the last time I saw you?
你信不信无所谓
You can believe it or not,
但我要告诉你  我什么都没做
but I'm telling you I didn't do anything.
-那是谁做的  -是我
- Then who did? - I did.
你说如果他跟阿卡迪亚基金有串通
You said if he colluded with Arcadian,
我们就可以逼他们出一大笔和解金
then we could shove a bigger settlement down their throats.
但他没必要勾结
But he didn't have to collude,
因为阿卡迪亚基金已经拿到那份和解协议了
because Arcadian already had access to that settlement.
这样无论如何都属于内幕交易
which makes it insider trading anyway.
我还向他们指出
And I pointed out to them
如果他们只把他们的股份
that if they were to divest their shares
抛售给那些不掌握内幕消息的客户
to our clients who don't have insider knowledge,
那他们就没有违法
then they've done nothing wrong.
没有造成损失
No harm done.
损失就是你害我失去了我客户
The harm is you lost me my client
还让我当了傻子
and made me look like a fool.
不  罗伯特  是他们拿你当了傻子
No, Robert, they did that
他们向你隐瞒了他们的作为
by not telling you what they did.
意味着你失去的这个客户
Which means the client you lost
早已违法了
was breaking the law.
更糟糕的是
And worse than that,
他们跟自己的律师撒谎
they were lying to their lawyer.
所以你觉得这很好玩吗
So you think this is funny?
没有  我没觉得
No, I don't.
我觉得你未来的女婿
I think your future son-in-law
相信你与此没有任何关系
trusted you had nothing to do with it
并且帮你避免了犯罪
and then saved your ass from committing a crime.
不...客气
You're...welcome?
谢谢
Thank you.
还有请你节哀
And you have my condolences.
-节什么哀  -因为要跟他打交道
- For what? - For having to deal with him.
你根本不理解有多麻烦
Oh, you have no idea.
看这里  我还在这里呢  伙计们
Hey, right here. I'm standing right here, guys.
我请你喝杯酒怎么样
Can I buy you a drink?
如果你们需要修补  挽救什么
If you guys, you know, need anything fixed or saved
别人不会的东西  随时找我
that no one else seems to be able to do, I'll be right here.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我想告诉你我有多么感激你
I wanted to tell you how grateful I am.
-你没必要这样  -不
- You don't need to do that. - Yes.
真的
I do.
这个烂摊子
This whole mess
是我经历过最艰难的事情
has been the hardest thing I've ever gone through.
如果没有你提醒我
And I wouldn't have gotten through it
真正重要的是什么  我不可能挺过来的
Without you reminding me what's really important.
谢谢你这么说
Thank you for that.
保重  哈维
Take care, Harvey.
祝你好运  埃斯特
Good luck, Esther.
顺便说一句
Oh, by the way,
路易也想让我告诉你
Louis wanted me to tell you
他非常感谢
how grateful he is too.
-哈维  -路易
- Harvey. - Louis.
要我帮你做什么
What can I do for you?
记得我说过  如果我要你
Remember when I said, if wanted you
弥补薪金投票的事情
to make up for the compensation vote,
我会直接来找你吗
I would come to you directly?
现在我就来了
Well, now I am.
那你说的
Well, what happened to
"生活中有些事情比钱更重要"又是怎么回事
"some things in life are more important than money"?
这跟钱没关系
This isn't about the money.
只是为了做正确的事情
This is about making things right.
我很抱歉  哈维
I'm sorry, Harvey.
为什么
For what?
我表现得像不知道埃斯特有多漂亮一样
I act like I don't know Esther's beautiful,
但我知道
But I do.
我们上初中的时候就开始了
It started when we were in junior high
所有型男都想跟我一起玩
and all the cool kids would hang out with me
这样他们就有机会接近她
just so they could get close to her.
有时候这招管用  有时候没用
Sometimes it worked, and sometimes it didn't,
但不论如何  这阶段一结束
But either way, when it was over...
他们都跟从不认识我一样
they all acted like they didn't know me at all.
所以当我想到
So when I thought
你在利用她来对付我  我就...
you were using her to get to me, I, uh--
我没那样  路易
I wasn't doing that, Louis.
我知道
I know.
我会处理好薪金的问题
I'll take care of the compensation issue.
需要我帮你做什么  哈维
What can I do for you, Harvey?
我想谢谢你
I wanted to thank you.
谢什么
For what?
你的十二年
For 12 years.